Viewers all over the world, whatever medium you are using to watch this service, I say, stay blessed.
[Amen.]
I am taking you to the book of Ephesians 3:17.
"Then Christ will make his home in your hearts."
Christ will make his home in your what?
[Heart.]
In your heart.
This means, that is the place Christ dwells.
That is the residence.
Many times we hear the song, "Inner my heart, Lord, I want to be like Jesus, inner my heart."
In our hearts, we want to be like Jesus, not in our face.
Here it says, "Christ will make his home in your hearts".
Our heart is the communication point – a dwelling place for Christ.
A contact.
If you are to hear from Christ, it is through your heart, not your ears.
Many would say, "Jesus, what are You saying?"
You can't hear Christ through your ears but your heart.
This makes it possible for us to talk to you and at the same time, to Christ
because we are not using the same medium.
I will use my mouth to talk to you and I will use my heart to talk to Jesus.
Jesus also will talk to me and at the same time, a man can talk to me
because it’s not the same medium.
If someone is telling you, "Look, I'm praying, don't disturb me" - I question his spirituality.
You can be talking to me and at the same time, I pray to Jesus.
We are not using the same medium.
As I am talking to you now, I am talking to Jesus.
Jesus is talking to me and I am talking to you at the same time.
I am praying and at the same time, I am talking to you because I'm not using the same medium.
Hallelujah.
OUR SUCCESS DEPENDS ON OUR MEDITATION AND CONFESSION
That is the topic this message.
Hallelujah.
“… as you trust in him. Your roots will grow down into God’s love and keep you strong."
Wow.
Christ will make your heart a dwelling place.
A dwelling place – a place of living – your heart.
Faith is of man’s heart.
Anywhere in the Bible that refers to heart, refers to the spirit.
Man’s heart and man’s spirit are the same.
Don't get confused.
Faith is of man’s heart, not of man’s body, flesh.
Only faith pleases God.
The Word of God builds Christ’s nature into us.
What builds Christ's nature?
The Word of God builds Christ’s nature into us, that is building Christ's nature into individuals.
When you want to end your letter as a Christian, you say, "In Him".
When your are writing a letter to a friend or... in the end you say, "In Him".
That is; in Him I live, move, talk – do all.
The Word builds Christ’s nature into us.
In other words, God is building Himself into us, making Himself a part of us
as the Word dominates, take note of that; building Himself into us
as the Word dominates, rules and satisfies our spirit nature.
This means faith is perfected by our acting on the Word.
Faith is perfected by our what?
[Acting on the Word.]
That is?
The Word must dominate us.
The Word must live in us.
This is the secret of faith.
We say; faith is perfected by our acting - it means; Word must dominate us, live in us...
If the Word has not dominated you, you cannot act faith.
The Word must dominate you, live in you – this is the secret of faith.
You can easily know a man of faith by a mere looking at his attitude.
Faith is not imitation – it cannot me imitated.
When you see a man "copying" people, imitating...
When you look around you say, "I like that style of a haircut. When I leave here, I am going to do the same.
Look at the suit this man wears - I am going to buy the same."
You keep comparing yourself to others; you are not content.
Faith is not imitation – it cannot by imitated.
It must arise in each person’s heart based on the Word of God because faith is of man's heart.
It must arise in each person’s heart according to the Word of God.
Because faith is of man’s heart.
That is faith.
When you see a man of faith, he doesn’t copy.
Follow the majority - no.
He does according to his heart.
He speaks according to his heart.
He doesn't look at the people's appearance; "this man is light in complexion - I'm going to bleach my body.
This man is slim - I'm going to do exercises to get slim.
This man has a very long hair - I'm going to tie something to my hair to get it long."
Faith does not neglect.
It does not neglect responsibilities.
Are your with me?
Faith does not neglect.
It does not neglect responsibilities.
You see a man of faith - this is a man who recognized his responsibilities.
It is easy to know the man of faith - it is simple, regardless of what they say
by mere looking at this formula you will able to know; "hey, it is not a man of faith".
Faith is not a panic button to push.
Oh, sorry, sorry, I have not fastened that button, please camera...
It is not a panic button to push only in times of trouble.
Today, you see Christians coming to God when they are in trouble; running to church for healing, praying,
reading the Bible - Psalm 35, putting it under the pillow, on the stomach...
They have nightmares - they run from place to place.
But when the going is smooth - you would not see them.
Faith is not a panic button to push only in times of trouble.
It is a lifestyle of trusting in God.
In the time of trouble they will say, "I rebuke in the name of..."
When you see people in trouble they will go for fasting of 3-4 days because they are in trouble.
That is not a man of faith.
Faith is a lifestyle of trusting in God.
When the going is good you see them praying, fasting - they do the same when the going is hard.
Faith is not a denial – it does not deny the existence of a problem.
When you are sick, you say, "I am sick" because they know that a man can be sick and yet be a friend of God.
Today, you learn that many ministers of God died suddenly - they have been sick for a long time
but they didn't want people to know that they were sick.
They were afraid that people would think the the sickness is a result of their sin.
So, they die suddenly.
Some of them commit suicide - ministers of God...
Faith is not a denial – it does not deny the existence of a problem.
We are still talking about faith.
The question - how come about faith?
Where can I get faith?
Where is the faith?
It does not originate from us.
If faith originates from saints, it would be fragile, weak.
I am talking of saints - s a i n t.
If faith originates from saints...
Not even you - you are not a saint.
Saint Apostles; if faith originates from them - it would be fragile, weak.
Faith originates from God.
This is why you must pay attention to God.
This is why you must pay attention to whom?
[God.]
What do I mean by 'pay attention to God'?
Look to God, look at God, meditate on God – you will have faith.
The more you look to God, look at God, meditate on God, the more you will have faith.
It comes spontaneously, naturally.
This is why you see many great ministers today who never attended any theology school.
This is why you see the rustic boy being raised as a great apostle today.
This is why you see a farmer or a fisherman becoming a great apostle -
without education, not being able to read a letter.
You will be surprised that he is not educated.
How come?
How somebody not educated can manage to be a great apostle and to preach the Word? - No
If faith originates in you; no illiterate would be raised, no rustic boy or fisherman
would become a great apostle.
If faith originates in you.
You would begin to look for a professor to anoint you.
You would begin to look for personalities, rich, great famous people to anoint you.
If faith originates in you.
This is why faith does not originate in you, it originates in God.
This is the area we Christians neglect today.
As a result of this our conversion becomes questionable.
You can know if your conversion is questionable.
When you cannot act with God and know God's opinion about yourself and others,
it means your conversion is questionable.
You may know the Bible from Genesis to Revelation - yet; something is missing.
What is missing?
No.
You may have faith but not enough.
The father of the demon-possessed boy came to Jesus saying, "I have brought my son to Your disciples,
they could not have delivered him because they had no power".
Jesus said, "No. They had power. Their faith was not adequate to release that power they needed."
Faith is a Heavenly currency.
The little currency you have is the little Heavenly material you can buy -
the little resources you can obtain.
Tell your neighbour, "Faith is a Heavenly currency."
[Faith is a Heavenly currency.]
You go to a market, you cannot purchase more than your money.
Your responsibility should not be greater than your spiritual life.
Today, our responsibility seems to be much more than our spiritual life.
Therefore, whatever blessing you receive, is like dropping a stone in the ocean.
If I'm talking to you.
Your responsibility seems to be much greater than your spiritual life.
Whatever blessing you now receive is like dropping a needle in the ocean.
When you receive a big blessing; by the time you get home you realize that it is not enough.
OUR SUCCESS DEPENDS ON OUR MEDITATION AND CONFESSION
My success depends on my meditation and confession.
Yes.
If you have been mediating before prayer, you will get to God.
You know I said it from the beginning, faith is not a panic button to push – only in time of trouble, you pray.
Only in times of trouble, you seek the face of God.
Only in times of trouble, you fast and pray.
Only in times of trouble, you begin to run helter skelter.
That is not faith.
Faith is a lifestyle of trusting in God.
How can you trust in God without mediation?
This is why I gave you faith-bracelets.
If you want to get it as a Christian - now meditation starts.
In your office, "Take more of me, oh God; give me more of You."
If you use it for one month - you don't need it.
It will become a habit to your heart to say, "Take more of me, give me more of You".
While you are talking to your boss, your heart would be saying, "take more of me, give me more of You".
While you are inside the bus, "take more of me, give me more of You".
While you are sitting down, your heart is supposed to be saying that, "take more of me, give me more of You".
If you are not saying it, and you are only looking at me; this means that this message will not get you
anywhere in your life.
You only hear it and you get it out of your head.
This is why you cannot make use of the message.
As you are looking at me now, your heart should be busy saying, "take more of me, give me more of You".
Oh Lord - give me more of You...
As you listen to me, continue to meditate on that.
Let that become your habit.
That is what you mean by a lifestyle of trusting in God.
It is not a prayer.
You pray only in time of trouble.
As you are looking at me, begin to engage your heart, "take more of me, give me more of You".
That is the best language to use for now.
Don't go too far.
I said to you at the beginning; the Word builds Christ's nature in us.
The Word builds what?
[Christ nature.]
Christ possesses a nature that makes it easy for me and you to trust in Him.
What is His nature?
His nature – faithfulness, kindness, goodness, self-control, humility, purity -
the fruits of the Spirit are the nature of Christ.
Take more of me; give me more of You.
That is the nature of Christ is what you demand for.
More of Your faithfulness, kindness, goodness, self-control, purity - because you are more of yourself.
More of yourself is unfaithfulness, disobedience, impurity.
More of yourself is disobedience.
More of yourself is opposite of the fruits of the Spirit.
You want Him to take more of you and give you more of Him.
Right now, I hope your heart is engaging in that.
Let me see if your heart is engaging that.
Right now it is a task.
When you leave here, when you will be eating, you will be in the restroom, nothing should stop your heart
from meditating on this.
While you are talking... - and I told you we are not using the same medium.
When you are talking, you are talking with your mouth to a man, and with your heart to God.
It is not the same medium.
You can do both at the same time.
Please, let me see your hand.
Your heart, right now, is engaging that.
Take more of me, give me more of You.
When you say, "Take more of me, give me more of You" that is -
more of God is faithfulness, kindness, goodness, self-control, purity,
obedience, humility – these are the nature of God.
This makes it possible for you to have faith.
This makes it possible for you to increase your faith.
You can increase your faith; you can have faith.
We have faith when we have more of the fruits of the Spirit – more of God.
The more your meditation, the more you have faith.
Please, let me see your hand.
So, you think that if you read the Bible from Genesis to Revelation that you have faith - no.
There is nothing bad about it - it is good to read the Bible.
Faith originates from God.
If faith originates from God, you must acknowledge His faithfulness and trustworthiness.
Acknowledging is by meditation in your heart.
Right now, let me see your hand if your heart is engaged in this now.
We want to stand up and promise that nothing will stop me,
nothing will break my heart, nothing will stop my heart from meditating.
Nothing; when I'm in the bedroom, when I'm eating, when I'm talking to my colleague...
Even you pastors, when you minister...
As I minister to you, my heart is yearning for this, my heart is communicating this, my heart is talking this.
My heart is saying something.
Take more of me...
Let me see your hand if your heart is meditating now.
Let's rise up and make a promise.
Everyday I talk about this.
You don't know how serious it is.
I don't know how you can grow; you can never, it is not possible.
Reading the Bible from Genesis to Revelation every week - that cannot make you grow.
You need God.
Viewers, anywhere you are, whatever medium you are using to view us right now,
I want you to join us in this promise before God.
The Lord says, "I will make your heart a dwelling place. I will make your heart My home".
How can God make our heart home when we are not inviting God into our heart?
This is an invitation to God.
Out of abundance of the heart, the mouth speaks.
Out of abundance of what?
[Heart.]
Some of you will say, "Out of abundance of the stomach".
What is in your stomach?
Rice.
Out of abundance of your stomach the restroom takes.
Out of abundance of what?
Say "Heart!"
[Heart.]
This is the language for Christians.
Not for others; others will say, "Out of abundance of the stomach."
It is not from our stomach.
Out of abundance of the heart, the mouth speaks.
When you are pregnant of God, you speak of God.
Viewers at home, nothing should stop you or break you from meditation.
OUR SUCCESS DEPENDS ON OUR MEDITATION AND CONFESSION
That is the topic of this message.
Say it again.
[OUR SUCCESS DEPENDS ON OUR MEDITATION AND CONFESSION]
But you believe our success depends on our prayer - the number of prayers you pray.
Which kind of prayer is that when you are not living the life of God and you are praying?
A break in faith is a break in God.
When you break in faith, you break in God.
Already, you have broken that relationship and you are now calling and inviting God to rescue you.
No - you must flow with God before you can pray.
Meditation makes you to flow with God.
A break in faith is a break in God.
In order not to break in faith, we must invite the nature of God.
Now - there should be no break.
Rise up your hand and make this promise - "Take more of me..." - speak it loud, before we register in our heart.
Oh Lord, take more of me; give me more of You.
More of Your faithfulness, honesty, obedience, purity, kindness, goodness, and self-control.
More of You...
This is what your heart should be yearning for all the time, should be speaking all the time.
Take more of me, give me more of You.
Because you are more of yourself, that is why you misbehave.
That is why we cannot control ourselves.
What we are not willing to do is what we find ourselves doing.
"I will not do this again" but you still go back and do it.
You have made a promise – "Take more of me; give me more of You".
Your lips should not move.
When your heart is talking, nobody would know it.
When your lips are moving, it shows that you are talking.
It is your heart that is talking this time.
There should be no break.
When you are about to sleep... yes - you are going on the wonderful journey.
You say this before going sleep - what a wonderful dream.
This is why you don't understand your dream; you have broken the relationship before you pray.
Tell your neighbour, "You have broken the relationship before you pray".
Whom are you praying with?
You have broken the relationship before you sleep.
Who will guide you?
Which is true of you?
Before now, you were just coming to the altar wanting to pray.
You have broken the relationship; now you are starting to pray...
You want to sleep; you have broken the relationship before sleeping.
This relationship should not be what?
[Broken.]
Should not be broken.
This is when you can carry God along.
This is like you have asked me to leave you and I left you.
Later, when you have a problem and you start to call me.
You start to call, "T.B. Joshua, please help".
You know that you have asked me to leave you.
That is the case of God.
A break in faith is a break in God.
Now, in order not to have that break again – meditation.
Meditation brings revelation.
Meditation in the Word of God is a visit with God.
When you continue to meditate, "Take more of me; give me more of You", you have visited God.
Before you know it, you begin to see revelation.
Before you know it, you dream a dream.
The promise of God will now come to your life.
You don’t need money to have peace.
You just need a revelation and relationship with God.
When God asks you, "Go to this place and get your money, contract, go and rest.
Today you are not going out".
OK - relax.
"Don't worry, go to this country; they will get you money. You need to rest .
You need to meet Me - go and fast for 3 days."
These are the things you need.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "You need an appointment with God".
[You need an appointment with God.]
You know; it is possible to have an appointment with God.
When you are eating, you are about to finish - God would say, "Stop. Meet Me."
That is fasting.
And you have eaten the half of the food - right now meet Me.
You wash your hands, you go straight to your bedroom, you lie down and start praying.
God says I should meet Him.
Appointment with God will change the course of your life.
You don't have an appointment with God.
Tell me, how long you hear God saying, "Go and meet this man - he will give you a business".
I want to stand here as a Prophet telling you today:
"The key I have given you today is the key of success."
Don’t be too excited and forget your meditation.
Tell your neighbour, "Don’t be too excited with whatever happens on the outside and forget your mediation."
Tell your neighbour again.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, this is what has happened.
Suddenly you see somebody saying, "I have a contract of 3 billion dollar".
You would be overwhelmed, "How much?"
You would forget your mediation because of money.
Just because you heard of such money you forgot about the meditation.
But when this man disappoints you, you will remember your mediation.
If I'm talking to you.
When you are disappointed you will do what?
You will remember your meditation.
That man says now, "I am sorry. I will not be able to do it".
Oh, take more of me; give me more of You.
If you see people rushing to pray - they have a problem.
That is not faith.
Faith is not a panic button to push only in times of trouble.
Faith is a lifestyle of trusting in God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Trust and obey
For there is no other way
To be happy in Jesus
But to trust and obey
This would not allow you to talk too much.
You would not talk too much, when you know that you are not like others.
You think you are like others when you are not here.
Here you are not like others, outside you are not like others, in the market you are not like others,
in the political party; when you are there negotiating - don't forget you are not like others.
Tell your neighbour, "Here, you are not like others."
[Here, you are not like others.]
Outside there, you are not like others.
[Outside there, you are not like others.]
At the bus stop, you are not like others.
[At the bus stop, you are not like others.]
In your political circle, you are not like others.
[In your political circle, you are not like others.]
In the market, you are not like others.
[In the market, you are not like others.]
In the business circle, you are not like others.
Don't forget, you are not like others!
[Don't forget, you are not like others.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are not like others, you have forgotten yourself.
Only when you are in church, you believe you are not like others.
Immediately you leave here, you forget what you stand for.
You have forgotten.
This is why you return to your past life.
This is why you return to your past glory.
You always return to your past glory.
If I have been returned to the past glory you would not come here today.
When you leave here, you forget yourself.
You are not like others.
Even inside the plane... at the airport, when you are sitting down, remember - you are not like others.
Your meditation - tell your neighbour, "You are not like others - your meditation".
It is your meditation that makes you different.
When you meditate with your heart, you will not have time to talk anyhow.
You will not give yourself to anything out there.
When you are at the airport to connect your flight, and it is delayed, you say, "Thank You, Jesus -
an opportunity to meditate".
But you - you say, "Oh my God. God will punish them."
Whom God will punish?
When your flight is delayed, it is an opportunity to meditate.
When you are inside the aircraft - "Wow, an opportunity to meditate".
You are not like others.
You only believe in prayer because the Bible says, "Prayer is the key".
Sing down there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Why can't you open that door?
Prayer is the key.
You fail to do what you need to do before the prayer.
The processing - there is a processing before the prayer.
You want to make a soup; you need so many ingredients to put together.
You need water, you need salt...
If any of these things misses it will give a different taste.
The soup will have a different taste.
The processing you need to pass through before prayer - you fail to pass through it.
Come brother.
This is God.
You have to get to God before you can call Him.
You can't stand here and say, "God!"
That is not a nature of God.
You need to meditate to get to God.
It is the meditation that will get you to God.
Now, it is time to pray.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Wait there.
The nature of God does not permit us to shout from here, "God! I need a biscuit, I need food!" - No.
It is wrong.
This is what you are doing.
Because from here to God there are so many obstacles, that will stop your voice from reaching God.
If I'm talking to you let me see your hand.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
From here to God there is so many obstacles; your unfaithfulness, unkindness, disobedience,
demon in your house, all sorts of things.
They are there to block your voice from reaching God.
Now, you have a role to play.
It is not all up to God and certainly, it is not all up to you.
You have a role to play and God has a role to play.
God is to hear you when you get to Him.
To get to Him, it is by meditation.
Meditation in the Word is a visit to God.
I'm going to visit God now.
Take more of me; give me more of You.
It will help me to overcome these obstacles.
If you get to God, you will know.
Your spirit will tell you that you are getting to God.
You'll hear voices in your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The closer you get to God the more you begin to sense the presence of holiness.
You will sense it immediately as you get closer to Him.
Now I'm here - I sense it: a visit with God.
Now, what do I need to do?
Lord, thank You for your grace, mercy...
He will tell you what to pray for.
Not you, dictating Him, but He will tell you what to ask for.
You should not ask; He will tell you what to demand for.
You should not demand.
Here.
This is the meaning of mediation.
When you get here, revelation will come.
Who gives revelation?
God!
Revelation does not come from us, human origin or senses but from God, just like faith we are talking about.
Now, you sense that revelation.
What is a revelation?
Revelation means He will tell you what to ask for, what to demand for, how to pray, when to pray -
that is revelation.
You may not be able to maintain this all days.
You are here already and you are supposed to stay here, and continue to be with God.
Because of the wall you find yourself against...
You go to work, you are working under, ... environment is not conducive - you go back.
That is why you should meditate all the time.
A break in meditation - you cannot get to God.
Please, don't be too excited and overwhelmed with what is on the outside and forget you meditation.
If you don't meditate, you cannot get revelation.
If you don’t have revelation, what are you praying for?
We don't know how to pray; the Holy Spirit teaches us.
Do you know that prayer has its own language?
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Right now, you have to bow down your head and say, "I will not break this relationship".
I will not break my meditation.
Nothing will be too exciting on the outside to make me break my meditation.
You have been given the anointed word: "Take more of me; give me more of You."
This is the anointed word given to you.
Right now, make this promise.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This makes you different from others.
When you are out there, you are not like others.
Others live life of the outside - what they see on the outside dictates their direction;
what you see on the inside dictates your direction.
What they see on the outside dictates their direction.
But you – you are not like others.
This is why you have to invite God into your heart.
God says, "I want to make your heart My home".
Right now begin to speak the word: Take more of me; give me more of You in your heart.
Believe it and He will bring it to pass.
Right now.
Begin to meditate this word in your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Meditate this word and believe it; He will bring it to pass.
In Jesus Christ's name.
[Amen.]
Thank You, Lord.
Hallelujah.
You may be seated.
Don't be too excited and forget your meditation.
Continue and this will become a lifestyle of trusting God.
Tell your neighbour, "A lifestyle of trusting God".
A lifestyle of trusting in God - I cannot hear you.
[A lifestyle of trusting in God.]
I cannot hear you.
Again and again.
[A lifestyle of trusting in God.]
Don't be afraid that you don't meditate while you are talking - no.
You can be saying it and at the same time the meditation continues.
The message you have received will come in your meditation.
Meditation will allow you to remember all you have seen and happened around you.
By meditation, you will have revelation about your friends -
there are many friends you have but they are not friends.
There are many companions you have but they are not.
People around you are so many – you need to know whom they are, what they stand for.
Thank You, Lord.
Hallelujah.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up to date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons and testimonies
from the Synagogue Church of all Nations
Emmanuel TV – changing lives, changing nations and changing the world.